Cristóbal Contreras Beltrán

Software Engineer - Frontend Developer

+56 9 95182311

in /in/cristobal-contreras

AsCraftC

Bē /AsCraftC

Profile

Software Engineer with experience in IT support, frontend development, User Experience(UX)/User Interfaces(UI) and User Centered Design(UCD). Skilled in implementing efficient technology solutions, from system configuration, administration and training to web application development. Knowledge in SQL and NoSQL databases, as well as backend integration and development (API and microservices). Focused on improving technological processes to maximize productivity and end-user satisfaction.

Areas of Expertise

Frontend development - UX/UI Design - Gamification - Game Design - Database - API REST - IT support - Windows Administrator - GNU/Linux - Network Administration - CPS.

Professional Experience

IT support, Villarrica Hospital

Villarrica, Chile 09/2024 - 10/2024

- Optimized user experience and streamlined daily tasks through effective configuration and repair of institutional equipment.
- Enhanced employee comfort and efficiency by configuring services, software, and office networks.
- Implemented agile response strategies for immediate problem resolution at operational points.
- Expertly administered, configured, and repaired Windows Office Systems to ensure smooth operation.

Frontend Developer, iDEAUFRO

Temuco, Chile 06/2023 - 12/2023

- Gathered and analyzed frontend project requirements to ensure alignment with client needs.
- Created wireframes and interactive mockups using Figma, covering a total of 7 views.
- Designed and developed web UI, applying User-Centered Design principles over 4 iterations.
- Integrated backend services using RESTful APIs and deployed servers with Docker.

IT support, <u>ASESORIAS Y GESTIONES TECNOLOGICAS SPA</u>

La Araucania, Chile 02/2021 - 04/2024

- Diagnosed and repaired hardware and software issues for printers.
- Configured and validated printer usage on LAN networks.
- Trained users on printer equipment usability and best practices.
- Optimized printer usage, increasing user productivity and reducing technical intervention needs.

Online Courses & Certifications

- Personal Cybersecurity Route (May. 2024) Platzi
- Git & GitHub Professional course (Jun. 2024) Platzi

Education

Ingeniería civil Informática Universidad de La Frontera

Temuco. Chile 2018-2023

Relevant Courses: Network Workshop, Computer Science 1 y 2, Databases 1 y 2, Requirements engineering, Computer Auditing, UX design, Cryptography and privacy, Software quality management, Project formulation and evaluation, Information Security, Internet of Things(IoT)

Skills

- Programming Languages & other: HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Java, SQL, Python, C#, Dart, GDScript, Arduino, LateX
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MariaDB
- Software & Frameworks: React, Astro Vue3, SASS, Springboot, Flutter, Unity, Godot, Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Figma, npm, git, git flow, GitHub, VSCode, Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, Windows (7, 10 y 11), GNU/Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS, ArchLinux, fedora, kali)
- Soft Skills: API REST consumption, IEEE-830 requirement documentation, UML, Unit tests, Responsive design, Scrum methodology, Effective Communication, Risk management

Languages

d--x English [B1]

drw- English [Technical]

drwx **Español** [Native]